## Paulo César Vieira Ruzanovsky

pauloruzanovsky@gmail.com ❖ +5547999487723 ❖ linkedin ❖ portfolio

Production Engineer with five years of experience in demand planning, proficient in data extraction, processing, and analysis, coupled with an expertise of Business Intelligence (BI) tools, practical experience in utilizing the SAP system.

## TECH KNOWLEDGE

Excel | Google Sheets | Python | SQL | BI | Qlik Sense | PowerBI | Tableau | ETL | SAP | Data Analysis | Optimization

## **EXPERIENCES**

Nidec GA
SnOE Senior Analyst

Joinville - SC, Brazil

SnOE Senior Analyst

Woodly, data systematics and manipulation from SAP to Everal stilling Puth on and SQL to transfer at the

- Weekly data extraction and manipulation from SAP to Excel, utilizing Python and SQL to transform the data into insights and developed visualizations on Qlik Sense, Power BI and Datastudio.
- I led a team of three demand analysts, ensuring optimized planning to maximize customer satisfaction, revenue, and minimize inventory and logistic costs. I addressed emergency situations by bridging departments such as Production Planning (PCP), Production Control and Materials (PCM), Manufacturing Engineering, Research and Development (R&D), and Sales to resolve issues like raw material shortages or operational challenges.
- I enhanced the efficiency of demand updating processes, reducing the time from 3 hours to 30 minutes. Utilizing Python, I automated the extraction of SAP data for analysis in Excel/Google Sheets, reducing the risk of human errors and enhancing the quality of inputted data.

Nidec GA Feb.2021 – Mar.2023

SnOE Mid-level Analyst

Joinville - SC, Brazil

- Leveling of production plans to ensure on-time deliveries and mitigate risks related to raw materials and manufacturing capacity.
- Development of performance indicators related to demand and production capacity using Qlik Sense.
- I streamlined frequently repeated demand analysis processes using Excel/Google Sheets, eliminating operational workload for the team.

Nidec GA Mar.2018 – Jan.2020

SnOE Intern

Joinville - SC, Brazil

- Providing support to the Sales and Operations Execution (S&OE) team in operational demand analysis tasks.
- Crafting automation tools for the demand planning process, leveraging my Excel expertise, leading to a substantial reduction in processing time.
- Designing and overseeing performance indicators utilizing tools such as Power BI and Google Datastudio.

## **EDUCATION**

Unisociesc Set.2023 – Set.2024

MBA em Business Intelligence, Management e Analytics

Joinville, SC

Udemy
Tableau 2022 A-Z: Hands-On Tableau Training for Data Science

Out.2023 – Out.2023 *Joinville, SC* 

Udemy

Set.2023 – Out.2023

SQL - MySQL for Data Analytics and Business Intelligence

Joinville, SC

Graduação em Engenharia de Produção e Sistemas

Joinville, SC